Guide to the Ricardo Sánchez Papers, 1941-1995
Department of Special Collections
- SERIES II: Correspondence, c. 1962-1994.
  - Subseries #1. General correspondence
    - Munoz, Rodolfo (1993-1994 ) (Box 29, Folder 54)
      prison issues: Frank N. Cervantes vs. Texas Department of Corrections; government conspiracy; National Movement of La Raza
    - Muriedas, Ramón (1984-1987) (Box 30, Folder 1)
      including brochure of Muriedas' art work (sculpture)
    - Murphy, Laura (students of) (1993) (Box 30, Folder 2)
      Yuma High School, Arizona
    - Museo del Arte Moderno (Mexico City) (1986) (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Naropa Instituta (Boulder, CO) (1989) (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - National Alliance of Third World Journalists (1988) (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - National Alternative Inner City Futures Project (1975, n.d.) (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - National Association for Chicano Studies (1997) (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - National Council of Teachers of English (1986) (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (1973-1978) (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (1979) (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (1979) Minority Report 1979 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (1979) Panelist Handbook (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (1979) Response... to the March 22, 1979 Report... (1979) (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - National Endowment for the Arts General Plan (draft) (1980-1984) (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, Information Packet (1980) (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (January-March, 1980) (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - National Endowment for the Arts April-September, 1980) (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (October-December, 1980) (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (1981) (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (1982-1992) (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, Lloyd Bentsen (1985) (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (n.d.) (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - National Enquirer - Aidé de León - Canto Aidé (1984) (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - National Interreligious Task Force on Criminal Justice (1977-1993) (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - National Peoples of Color Task Force on Criminal Justice (1988) (Box 31, Folder 6)
      National Interreligious Task Force on Criminal Justice
    - National Research Council (1982) (Box 31, Folder 7)
      Postdoctoral Fellowships for Minorities
    - Negri, Guglielmo, Centro di Studi Americani (Rome) (1989) (Box 31, Folder 8)
      Franca Bacchiega; The Chicanos
    - Nicacio, Maria and Jaime (1993) (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Nichols, John (1988-1989) (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Nickerson, Sheila (1979-1981) (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Nickerson, Sheila (1982) (Box 31, Folder 12)
      "Waiting for the News on Death"
    - Nieto, Davíd (1980) (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Nieto, Ernest, National Hispanic Institute (n.d.) (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - [Nineteen] 1992 Re...view (1989) (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Norman, Arthur (1988-1991) (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Nosotros: Human Services Development, Inc. (1987) (Box 31, Folder 17)
      Ruben Blades
    - Notebook: A Little Magazine (1987) (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Oandasan, William (n.d.) (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - O'Brien, Mark Ellis (1980) (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Ocasio, Heriberto, International Emergency Committee (1993) (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Olvera, Joe (1983-1985) (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Onofre, Anisa (1990-1991) (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Orona Gandara, Mago (1978-1980) (Box 31, Folder 24)
      Art Forum article by Hal Marcus, autographed by Mago Orona
    - Ortego y Gasca, Felipe de (1992, n.d.) (Box 31, Folder 25)
      "Hispanic Journal on Running and Philosophy of Life" ;The National Hispanic Reporter (Feb. 1992); WSU Week (Feb. 1992) ;"Canto a Felipe Ortego" (1992)
    - Ortiz, Mary (1987-1988) (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Ortiz, Simon and Joy (1973) (Box 31, Folder 27)
      Rainy Dawn Ortiz
    - Ortiz, Verónica (1986) (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Osante, Ana (1991-1993) (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Osif, Annaleta and the Navajo Nation (1975-1993) (Box 31, Folder 30)
      Eunice McCabe, "Offering"; American Indian Biographies; "Sharing Time: Oct. 7th." by Leornad Ignacio, Navajo
    - Osif, Annaleta, the Navajo Nation (c. 1990) (Box 31, Folder 31)
      "To-dan-nas-sha Baha'ne: Kayenta, Arizona, 1900-1990"
    - Otey, Harold LaMont (Will) (1991) (Box 31, Folder 32)
    - Overton, John (1982-1983) (Box 31, Folder 33)
      Primal Gardens: studio exhibition
    - Pacheco, Javier (1969-1974) (Box 31, Folder 34)
      various manuscripts and articles
    - Pacheco, Javier (1975-1976) (Box 31, Folder 35)
    - Pacheco, Javier (1977-1981) (Box 31, Folder 36)
    - Pacheco, Javier (1982-1984) (Box 31, Folder 37)
    - Pacheco, Javier (1988-1993) (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Pacheco, Javier (n.d.) (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Padilla, Joanna (1994) (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Padilla, Rudy (1989-1993) (Box 32, Folder 4)
      packet of clippings, etc.; Chicano Folk Art: Paño (handkerchief) Arte South Broadway Cultural Center (Alburquerque); Manuel Acosta "Blood In... Blood Out"; Lowriding Magazine
    - Pajarito Publications (1977) (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Pañay [?], Silvia [1992?] (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Paperbacks Plus (1989) (Box 32, Folder 7)
      Marquetta and John Eliot
    - Parada, Ramón, La Familia Counseling Service (1984) (Box 32, Folder 8)
      Razalogia: Community Learning for a New Society
    - Parra, J.A. [Jose Antonio] (1973) (Box 32, Folder 9.1)
    - The Pawn Review (1981) (Box 32, Folder 9.2)
    - Paz, Juan (1982) (Box 32, Folder 9.3)
    - Panther House Limited (1970) (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Parker, Mary Magdalene (1985-1987) (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Parker, Mary Magdalene (1988-1993, n.d.) (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Peck, Claudia, Washington State University (1994) (Box 32, Folder 13)
      Steven Roos
    - PEN - Nelson Algren Fiction Award (1985) (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - PEN American Center (1975-1981) (Box 32, Folder 15)
      PENewsletter
    - Peña, Amado Maurilio (1981) (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Peña, Juan Jose, Raza Unida Party (1978-1979, n.d.) (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Peña, Juan Jose (1987) (Box 32, Folder 18)
      manuscripts
    - Peña, Juan Jose (1990) (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Pena, Rene, Children's Television Workshop (1994) (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Pennyworth, Cameron [?] (n.d.) (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Pepinsky, Indiana University (1989-1991) (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Peterson, Dawn (1980-1981) (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Picante Magazine (1978) (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Pierces, Jim (1981-1991) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Piña, Antonio (1991) (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Piñón, Becky (1989) (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Poets and Writers, Inc. (1977-1982) (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Posset, Benn (1980-1981) (Box 33, Folder 5)
      SOYO Productions One World Poetry
    - Pollitzer, Joanne (1985) (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Portland Public Schools (1991) (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Pozzi, Gian (1981) (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Prentice Hall (1990) (Box 33, Folder 9)
      "i yearn" in A Historty of the United States by Boorstin and Kelley
    - Publisher's Weekly (1971) (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Puerto del Sol (n.d.) (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Pulido, Alberto, NAES Conference (1992) (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Qué Viva Dallas Magazine (n.d.) (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Quiñones, Rogelio (1992) (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Quintanal, Maria Pérez (1989) (Box 33, Folder 15)
      manuscript
    - Rábago, Silvana (1992) (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Rakocy, Bill (1981) (Box 33, Folder 17)
      "The True Face of History" from Despotism: A Pictoral History of Tyranny
    - Ramirez, Axel (1992) (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Ramirez, Isela, Riverside High School (El Paso) (1989) (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Ramirez, Raymond L. (1985) (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Ramirez, Salvador, Chicano Studies, Washington State University (1974) (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Rangel, Andrew (1988) (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - Razo, Augustin del (1980) (Box 33, Folder 23)
      "septiembre mexico"
    - Rediscover America Poll (1992) (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Regional Arts Conference and Showcase (Corpus Christi, Texas) (1986) (Box 33, Folder 25)
      Center for Hispanic Arts at the Multicultural Center: "Figurative Artists"
    - Reid, Kay (n.d.) (Box 33, Folder 26)
      "The Children Cried"
    - Rendón, Gloria (1981-1984) (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - Rentería, Joe R. (n.d.) (Box 33, Folder 28)
      Carmen Barron Chagra Brothers
    - Rentería, Luis (family of) (1971) (Box 33, Folder 29)
      Carmen Barron Trust Fund
    - Reyes, Abel (1992) (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - Reyes, Jo Anne (1988-1992) (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - Reyna, Mauro, Ysleta Independent School District (1989) (Box 33, Folder 32)
      Riverside High School
    - Riewald, Sally (1991) (Box 33, Folder 33)
    - Rio Grande Review (El Paso) (1991) (Box 33, Folder 34)
      "Across the Lines" reading
    - Rista, L. (1976) (Box 33, Folder 35)
    - Rivera, Carlos (1972) (Box 33, Folder 36)
      manuscript: "Blessed Are They"
    - Riverside High School, El Paso (1989) (Box 33, Folder 37)
    - Robinson, Lewis / Akron OIC (1972) (Box 33, Folder 38)
    - Robinson, St. John (1985) (Box 33, Folder 39)
    - Rocard, Marcienne (1992) (Box 33, Folder 40)
    - Rodarte, Frank (1987-1990) (Box 33, Folder 41)
    - Rodis, Lenore B. (1987) (Box 33, Folder 42)
    - Rodriguez, Alberto (1982) (Box 33, Folder 43)
    - Rodriquez, Felipe (1980) (Box 33, Folder 44)
    - Rodriguez, Juan Antonio (1976-1978) (Box 33, Folder 45)
    - Rodriguez, Roberto (1988) (Box 33, Folder 46)
      Americas 2001
    - Rodriguez, Rosamaria (1992) (Box 33, Folder 47)
    - Roman, Javier, Dos Mundos (1994) (Box 33, Folder 48)
    - Romero, Jose and Victoria (1976) (Box 33, Folder 49)
    - Romero, Orlando (1982) (Box 33, Folder 50)
      Mesquite readings series at Paperbacks Plus "Panic Among the Philistines" by Bryan F. Griffin
    - Romero Insurance Agency (1989) (Box 33, Folder 51)
    - Roosevelt School, 6th grade class (1991) (Box 33, Folder 52)
    - Rosas, Carlos (1975-1979) (Box 34, Folder 1)
      La Voz Hispana de Colorado (July, 1977) drawing of Sánchez
    - Rosas, Carlos, notebook (1980) (Box 34, Folder 2)
      photos and slides of art work (paintings and murals)
    - Rosas, Carlos (1980-1982) (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Rosas, Carlos (1983-1992) (Box 34, Folder 4)
      includes photos
    - Rosas, Carlos (n.d.) (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Ross, Mary (1980) (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Rossignol, James (1985-1992, n.d.) (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Rossow, Josué Ybarra (1984-1986) (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Roth Publishing (1986) (Box 34, Folder 9)
      "Toward" and "I Remember" in anthology
    - Rucker, Ellie (1982) (Box 34, Folder 10)
      The Austin American-Statesman
    - Russell, Philip (1984) (Box 34, Folder 11)
      Colorado River Press
    - Saenz, José M. (Chema) (1978-1982, n.d.) (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Saenz, Jose (Chema) and Anna (1991-1992) (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Sagel, Jim (1979) (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Salas, Jesus (1983-1988) (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Salas, Ricardo (1981) (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Salazar, Anthony and Catherine Shaughnessy (1980) (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Salinas, Raúl (1982-1983, n.d.) (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - San Antonio Business Committee for the Arts (1987) (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - San Antonio Express-News (1983) (Box 34, Folder 20)
      Paperbacks... y mas
    - San Antonio Festival (1984-1987) (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - San Antonio Independent School District (1988) (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - San Antonio Light (1989) (Box 34, Folder 23)
      freelance copyrights
    - San Antonio Literacy Council, Inc. (1984) (Box 34, Folder 24)
      Margarita R. Huantes
    - San Antonio Museum of Art (1987) (Box 34, Folder 25)
      "Influence" exhibition "Mira!" exhibition
    - San Antonio Public Library (1983-1986) (Box 34, Folder 26)
      Irwin "Mike" Sexton Young Pegasus Poetry Contest
    - San Antonio Retail Merchant Association (1988) (Box 34, Folder 27)
    - San Antonio Science Fiction Association (1987) (Box 34, Folder 28)
    - Sánchez, Alejandro (1990) (Box 34, Folder 29)
    - Sánchez, Allen (1971) (Box 34, Folder 30)
      nephew
    - Sánchez, Armando (1981) (Box 34, Folder 31)
    - Sánchez, Brian and Esther (1974) (Box 34, Folder 32)
      Francisco Cuatémoc Sánchez y Martinez
    - Sánchez, Jacqueline, Latino Poets Association (1990) (Box 34, Folder 33)
    - Sánchez, Lena C. (1969, 1981-1982) (Box 34, Folder 34)
      mother
    - Sánchez, Manuel Romero de (Mannie) (1970-1986, n.d.) (Box 34, Folder 35)
      brother John Patrick Tafoya (nephew)
    - Sánchez, Natividad-Nekáme Silva (1987) (Box 34, Folder 36)
      grandson
    - Sánchez, Richard (1988) (Box 34, Folder 37)
    - Sánchez, Rikárd-Sergei (1972-1984, n.d.) (Box 34, Folder 38)
      son Libertad-Yvonne (daughter)
    - Sánchez, Rose (1976-1983, n.d.) (Box 35, Folder 1)
      sister
    - Sánchez, Teresa (1972-1992, n.d.) (Box 35, Folder 2)
      wife
    - Sánchez, Trinidad (1987-1991) (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Sánchez, Tyrone and Lydia (1975) (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Sandoval, Rubén (1981) (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Santana, Carlos, Management (1988) (Box 35, Folder 6)
      Refuse and Resist! -Resist in Concert
    - Santos, Gonzalo (1987) (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Sauzo, Eluid Pete (1979) (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - School for Educational Enrichment (1989) (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Schroeder, Dave (n.d.) (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Seibles, Tim (1987) (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Sen, Debasis (1992) (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - SER (Service Employment Redevelopment) (19878-1980) (Box 35, Folder 13)
      "A Decade of Progress" 1974-1975 annual report assorted SER literature
    - Shaddox, Brenda (1985) (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Silva, M. Estela (1979-1984, n.d.) (Box 35, Folder 15)
      mother of Teresa Silva Sánchez
    - Sikélianos, Eleni (1990) (Box 35, Folder 16)
      NAROPA Institute
    - Simpson, Bob (1981) (Box 35, Folder 17)
      Texas House of Representatives
    - Slate, Audrey (1983) (Box 35, Folder 18)
      The Dobie-Paisano Project
    - Socarcega, Pamela (1988) (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Sociedad para los Artes, NMSU (Cherie Lievsay) (1988) (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Sonora Review (1988) (Box 35, Folder 21)
      "Crossing Boundaries: Writing from Alternative Traditions" feature
    - Soto, Gary (1980) (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Southwest Texas Junior College (1983, 1986) (Box 35, Folder 23)
      Creative Arts Fair, Readings
    - Spokane Falls Community College (1994) (Box 35, Folder 24)
      Student of Color Conference
    - Stanuch, Claude (n.d.) (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Stephens, Tootsie (1992) (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Stew Press (n.d.) (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Stochard, Connie (1982) (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Stovall, Linny, Blue Heron Publishing (1993) (Box 35, Folder 29)
      Left Bank #5: Borders & Boundaries "Fronteras"
    - Stovall, Margaret (1987) (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - Stracham, Geoffrey, Methuen London (1988) (Box 35, Folder 31)
      Les Suerostraats of Big Cotulla
    - Stratz, Jim (1990) (Box 35, Folder 32)
      National Arts Society of Pass Christian, MS "LOVE STREWN SANDS" in Poems of Great America, Vol. 3
    - Sunwest Bank (El Paso) (1990) (Box 35, Folder 33)
    - Sutton, Patricia (1971) (Box 35, Folder 34)
    - Switzer, Betty (1987) (Box 35, Folder 35)
    - Taatgen, Dick (1990) (Box 35, Folder 36)
      Indiana University Department of Criminal Justice
    - TAMACS (Texas Association of Mexican American College Students) (Arlington, TX), (1990, n.d.) (Box 35, Folder 37)
    - Tanguma, Ramon (1971) (Box 35, Folder 38)
    - Taylor, Chuck (1976) (Box 35, Folder 39)
      The Texas Slough magazine; Paul Foreman: Quanah Parker: A Name-Dream David Gene Fowler; Rosendo Ivanov Reyes; John Garmon; William Varela; Naomi Shibab; Edward Field; Hal Marcus; Robert Grant Burns
    - Taylor, Chuck (1978) (Box 35, Folder 40)
      Great Salt Lake Anthology; "The Fix: A Political Poem"; "Leo (a round of poems)" The Great Salt Lake Newspaper (July 1978)
    - Taylor, Chuck (1980) (Box 35, Folder 41)
    - Taylor, Chuck (1981) (Box 35, Folder 42)
    - Taylor, Chuck (1982) (Box 35, Folder 43)
      Texas Circuit, Austin Arts Commission: METRO-PAC, Downtown Literature Series, Alice Adam
    - Taylor, Chuck (1987-1988) (Box 35, Folder 44)
      National Arts Week '87: "Images and Words, Words and Images"
    - Taylor, Chuck (1989) (Box 35, Folder 45)
    - Taylor, Chuck (1990) (Box 35, Folder 46)
    - Taylor, Chuck (1991) (Box 35, Folder 47)
    - Taylor, Chuck (1992-1993) (Box 35, Folder 48)
    - Taylor, Chuck (n.d.) (Box 35, Folder 49)
      Nonviolent Anarchist Newsletter
    - Taylor, Pat Ellis (1981) (Box 35, Folder 50)
      Hotsprings Information Network; "Afoot In a Field of Men"
    - Taylor, Pat Ellis (1982) (Box 35, Folder 51)
      "Leaping Leo"
    - Taylor, Pat Ellis (1985) (Box 35, Folder 52)
      "Have: Journal of an Austin Plague Year"
    - Taylor, Pat Ellis (1987) (Box 35, Folder 53)
    - Taylor, Pat Ellis (1988-1989) (Box 35, Folder 54)
    - Taylor, Pat Ellis (n.d.) (Box 36, Folder 1)
      "A Neighbor at the Door' "At Home on the Range"D
    - Taylor, P.J. (1982) (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Tello, Victor (1985-1989, n.d.) (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Tercer Acto (n.d.) (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Texas A & I University at Corpus Christi (1975) (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Texas Commission on the Arts (1974-1977) (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Texas Commission on the Arts (1985-1988, n.d.) (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Texas Committee for the Humanities (1982) (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Texas Institute of Letters (1984) (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Texas Prisons Hunger Strike (1989) (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Thinker Review (n.d.) (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Thomas, Lorry (1991) (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Thurston, Linda (1987-1992) (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Tiffany, Georgia (n.d.) (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Tilton, John (1989-1990) (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Tobias, Lucio (1981) (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Torres, Priscilla (1989) (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - TQS Publications (1991) (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Travis County (Texas) (1983) (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Treviño, David (1973) (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Treviño, Gloria (1979) (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Treviño, Rudy, Tejano Music Awards (1988) (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Tricontinental Film Center (1971-1973) (Box 36, Folder 23)
      formerly Third World Cinema Group
    - Trinity Association for Chicano Students (1974) (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Trinity University News (1985) (Box 36, Folder 25)
      Carolyn Forche
    - Trujillo, Roberto, Green Library, Stanford (1993) (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Trujillo, Rogelio (1980) (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - UCLA, Chicano Studies Center (1975) (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Utah Holiday (1981) (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - United Airlines (1993) (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (San Antonio) (1987-1988) (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - University of Houston Libraries, Special Collections (1976) (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - University of South Carolina Press (1989) (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - University of Texas at Austin, Benson Latin American Collection (1980-1991) (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - University of Texas at Austin, Chicano Studies (1980) (Box 36, Folder 35)
    - University of Texas at El Paso, Chicano Studies / Issues (1988) (Box 36, Folder 36)
    - University of Texas at El Paso, Library (n.d.) (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - University of Texas at El Paso, Social Work Program (1979) (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - University of Texas Press (1979) (Box 36, Folder 39)
      Interview with Sánchez in Chicano Authors: Inquiry by Interview by Bruce-Novoa
    - University of Wisconsin at Milwaukee (1977-1978) (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - University Press of the Americas (1991) (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - U.S. Dept. of Justice, Bureau of Prisons (1970) (Box 36, Folder 42)
    - Utah Migrant Council (1980) (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - Utah Policy / Advisory Council on Hispanic Affairs (1980) (Box 36, Folder 44)
    - Vaca, Nick, Quinto Sol Publications (1970) (Box 36, Folder 45)
    - Valdez, Jim (1986-1993) (Box 36, Folder 46)
      Instituto Cultural Mexico
    - Vargas, Martin Quetzalcoatl (1978) (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - Vasquez, Abraham (1992) (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Vasquez y Sánchez, Ramon, Centro Cultural Aztlan (1986) (Box 36, Folder 49)
    - Vasquez y Sánchez, Ramon, Centro Cultural Aztlan (1987) (Box 36, Folder 50)
      Viaztlan
    - Vellegas, Jennifer (1992) (Box 36, Folder 51)
    - Vento, A. C. (1978-1980, n.d.) (Box 36, Folder 52)
    - Vento, A. C. (1986-1989) (Box 36, Folder 53)
    - Villanueva, Armando (1977) (Box 36, Folder 54)
    - Villanueva, Tino (1977-1988) (Box 36, Folder 55)
    - Villaseñor, Victor (1980-1981) (Box 36, Folder 56)
    - Vinkenoog, Simon, One World Poetry (1979-1983) (Box 36, Folder 57)
    - von Honts, Jacqueline (1989) (Box 36, Folder 58)
    - Washington, Jerome (n.d.) (Box 36, Folder 59)
    - Washington State University, "Crossing Borders: Chicano Realities" Conference (1992-1993) (Box 37, Folder 4)
      Includes various non-correspondence, related materials Abelardo Delgado, Felipe de Ortego y Gasca, Jesus "El Flaco" Maldonado, Felipe Duran, John Prater, Franca Bacchiega, Mago Orona-Gandara, Tomás Villanueve, Javier Aguirre, William Willard, Priscilla Falcón, Charles Potts, Miguel Lopez on John Rechy and Amalia Gomez, Ben Olguin, Maria Teresa Sánchez, Jaime Nolan on Sandra Cineros, Bernice Zamora, Wendy Swyt on Helena Maria Viramontes, Nan Macy, Mary Kay Downing on Yaqui Religious arts, Dorcas McCoy, Ed Hernandez, Javier Pacheco, Roberto Trujillo, Norma Duran, Susan Armitage, Kathleen Burrage, Melinda Antoni, John Donelly, Gisela Ernst, Bonnie Frederick, John Kicza, Tim Reed, Dennis West, Manuel Acosta, Bilingual Education issues: Sonia Nieto: "Equity in Education", Katherine E. Snow; Alan Barnett, "Community Murals", Gloria Anzaldua,
    - Washington State University, Berta Garza (1992) (Box 37, Folder 5)
      Includes various non-correspondence, related materials
    - Washington State University, MEChA Conference (1991) (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Washington State University, minority affairs (1991-1992, n.d.) (Box 37, Folder 7)
      Includes various non-correspondence, related materials International Week (1993)
    - Washington State University, readings (1992) (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Washington State University, "Ricardo's Universe" television show (1991-1992) (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Washington State University, teaching (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Washington State University, tenure and promotion process (1994) (Box 37, Folder 11)
      "On My Academics: Candidate Statement"
    - Washington State University, tenure and promotion process, honors and awards: letters of recommendation for Sánchez (1992-1994) (Box 37, Folder 12)
      Francisco Morales, Scott McLean, Steve Nakata, Susan Armitage, Felipe Duran, Samuel H. Smith, William Willard, Norma Duran,Eileen Oliver, Merrill Franklin Danford,
    - Watchman, J. and others (n.d.) (Box 37, Folder 13)
      "Our Brother" poem for Sánchez
    - Watershed Tapes (1992) (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Werts, Gina and Richard Yzaguire (1992) (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Whitman County District Court (1993) (Box 37, Folder 16)
      jury duty
    - Wiley, John and Sons, Inc. (1972) (Box 37, Folder 17)
      Points of Departure
    - Wilkinson, John, New Mexico State University (n.d.) (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Willard, William (1993) (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Williams, Galen (1982) (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - Williams, Lucille (1980) (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Wilson, Gene-K (1990-1991) (Box 37, Folder 22)